Finding Aid for A. Alfred Taubman papers, 1942-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Athena Azerbaijan and Russia Development Projects 1995-2002
  - Balchug Plaza
    - Balchug #1 (through 6/30/96) (Box 234)
    - #2 (7/1/96 through 10/15/96) (Box 234)
    - #3 (10/6/96 through 12/31/96) (Box 234)
    - #4 (1/1/97 through 3/31/97) (Box 234)
    - #5 (4/1/97 through 4/30/97) (Box 234)
    - Balchug #6 (5/1/97 through 7/15/97) (Box 234)
    - #7 (7/16/97 through 8/31/97) (Box 234)
    - #8 (9/1/97 through 12/31/97) (Box 234)
    - #9 (1/1/98 through 3/31/98) (Box 234)
    - #10 (4/1/98 through 5/31/98) (Box 234)
    - #11 (6/1/98 through 6/30/98) (Box 234)
    - #12 (7/1/98 through 8/31/98) (Box 235)
    - #13 (9/1/98 through 9/23/98) (Box 235)
    - Parking (Box 235)
    - Codes (Box 235)
    - ECOS report (Box 235)
    - Engineering: mechanical/electrical (Box 235)
    - General correspondence (Box 235)
    - Public relations/publicity (Box 235)
    - Meeting agendas and minutes (Box 235)
    - S&T correspondence (Box 235)
    - Project summary draft and drawings (Box 236)
    - Balchug office/retail development summary information June 18, 1997 (Box 236)
    - Balchug master plan (correspondence and memos) 1996-1997 (Box 236)
    - Balchug drawings January 1996 (includes drawings marked "AAT's own tissue") (Box 236)
    - Balchug drawings August 15, 1996 (Box 236)
    - Photograph and color copies of architect's model (Box 236)
    - Floor plans (Box 236)
    - Pomplemousse new member (Box 236)
    - Capital call letters (Box 236)
    - Agreements (Box 236)
    - Siemens request for proposal (Box 236)
    - Status reports (Box 236)
    - Balchug Cyprus Ltd. agreements (Box 236)
    - Balchug drawings and cost schedule (Box 236)
    - Balchug working files 1996-2001, 59 folders (Box 237)
    - Balchug, general contractors (Box 237)
    - Balchug memos, plans, and financial (Box 237)
    - Balchug/OPIC (Box 237)
    - Balchug joint venture agreement (Box 237)
  - Moscow Logistics Park
    - Magest, Inc. proposal (Box 238)
    - Project summary (Box 238)
    - Investment summary (Box 238)
    - Technical reports (Box 238)
    - Construction and project summary (Box 238)
    - Bank statements (Box 238)
    - Balance sheets (Box 238)
    - Purchase and sale agreements (Box 238)
    - Legal files (Box 238)
    - Moscow Logistics Park capital (Box 238)
    - Moscow Logistics Park (Box 238)
    - CMC Stroi loan (Box 239)
    - MLP Cyprus bank accounts (Box 239)
    - Butler/Magest litigation (Box 239)
    - Marketing (Box 239)
      (includes slides and notes for Bob Rylee's talk on MLP and other Athena projects)
    - Potential tenants (Box 239)
    - Short-term loan (Box 239)
    - Ground lease (Box 239)
    - 2001 offering (Box 239)
    - Design issues: Burt Hill initial concepts (Box 239)
    - Nikolai Worp (consultant) expenses (Box 239)
    - Investors (Box 239)
    - Investor updates (Box 239)
  - Four Winds
    - Financials (Box 240)
    - Development overview (Box 240)
    - Four Winds/Tajir Family memorandum of understanding (Box 240)
    - Ladbroke (Box 240)
    - Site contract (Box 240)
    - Drawings (Box 240)
    - Four Winds Plaza (Box 240)
    - Four Winds plans (Box 240)
  - Leninsky Prospekt
    - Leninsky Prospekt (Box 240)
    - Financials (Box 240)
    - Drawings (Box 240)
    - Offering memorandum (Box 240)
    - Cost schedules (Box 240)
    - Market research data (Box 240)
    - LMD files (Box 240)
    - Retail market information (Box 240)
  - City of Moscow buyout
    - City of Moscow buyout (Box 242)
    - Mosproject 2 correspondence (Box 242)
  - Ernst & Young (Box 242)
  - Miscellaneous plans
    - Russian superstores plans (Box 242)
    - Misc. plans (Box 242)
  - Athena/S&T trading agreement (Box 242)
  - Athena/Moscow due diligence documents (Box 242)
  - Moscow trip May-June, 1998 (Box 242)
  - Moscow development project summaries (Box 242)
  - St. Petersburg/Potential developments with Soyuzkontrakt (Box 242)
  - Moscow restaurants (Box 242)
  - Bob Rylee correspondence October 1995-June 1996 (Box 242)
  - Lease (Box 242)
  - MBNDC lease renegotiation (Box 243)
  - HOK sub-lease (Box 243)
  - Landlord (Box 243)
  - Telephone service (Box 243)
  - Tverskaya apartment (Box 243)
  - HOK rent payment (Box 243)
  - Athena entity (Box 243)
  - Expenses/personnel (Box 243)
  - Don Missey, cash (Box 243)
  - Furniture (Box 243)
  - Office equipment (Box 243)
  - Anna Semenova (Box 243)
  - Chalva letter of intent February 2002 (Box 243)
  - Additional S-T projects (Box 243)
  - Russian/Eastern European fund offerings, 12 folders (Box 243)
  - Versity Weekly and Top Secret Consortium (Box 243)
  - Athena Russia Fund (Box 243)
  - AIG office headquarters (Box 243)
  - Nomura conference (Box 243)
  - Quasi-government bodies (Box 243)
  - OPIC meeting (Box 243)
  - S&T Group (Box 243)
  - Athena Moscow projects (Box 243)
  - Manezhnaya Square 1995, construction plans (Tube 1)
- Exhibit / Posters
  - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman", 12 panels
    (The panels include photographs together with a time-line of significant events in Taubman's career)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 1)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 2)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 3)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 4)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 5)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 6)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 7)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 8)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 9)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 10)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 11)
    - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman" (Object 12)
  - Exhibit produced by Lawrence Technological University in 2012 entitled "Pioneering the Purchase: A Retrospective Exhibition Honoring A. Alfred Taubman", 1 optical disks CD-Rs (Box 225)
  - Rolled poster containing mosaic of scanned photographs of proposed malls in Tampa, Salt Lake City, Short Hills, New Jersey, etc. (Tube 2)
  - Rolled display poster containing logos of AAT businesses and investments (Tube 3)